const e="crk",t=200,o=120,a=[{id:74,question:"“There shall be neither dew nor rain this year except by my word” Who said this?",option:{a:"Moses ",b:"Pharaoh ",c:"Elijah ",d:"Esther "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:75,question:"In the case before Solomon over the deal and the living, child the mother of the dead child supported. ",option:{a:"Giving the living child to her opponent ",b:"Killing the living child ",c:"joint ownership of the living child ",d:"king Solomon having the living child"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:76,question:"Before Moses died. God appointed ………. to succeed him ",option:{a:"Aaron ",b:"Balaam",c:"Joshua ",d:"Manasseh "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:77,question:"Those bitten by the serpent were treated by ",option:{a:"Drinking from the Red sea ",b:"fasting for seven day ",c:"looking at the bronze serpent ",d:"call upon the lord "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:78,question:"In order that Benjamin might be brought to Egypt, Joseph detained ",option:{a:"Ruben ",b:"Levi ",c:"Jacob ",d:"Simoen "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:79,question:"Those inspired by God to lead the tribes of Israel in battle were the ",option:{a:"Judges  ",b:"Captains of Guard  ",c:"priest  ",d:"prophet  "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:80,question:"God told Samuel that he, would punish Eli because he  ",option:{a:"did not correct his son’s sinful behavior ",b:"did not offer sacrifice as the: Law ",c:"did not warn the people of Israel to stop surfing ",d:"Warned his sons against rape and drunkenness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:81,question:"The sun stood still when ",option:{a:"Moses led Israel across the Red sea ",b:"Jericho fell to the army of Joshua ",c:"Noah came out of the ark ",d:"Joshua defeated the Amorite at Gideon "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:82,question:"Who is reputed for pulling down the altar of Baal at the risk of annoying his father? ",option:{a:"Joseph ",b:"Jesse ",c:"Gideon   ",d:"Samuel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:83,question:"In the trade treated between King Solomon and Lebanon, Solomon was to supply wheat and oil while Hiram was to supply",option:{a:"Grains only ",b:"precious stories ",c:"wheat advice ",d:"Timber "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:84,question:"Which prophet cried thus “woe is me” for lost, I am a man of unclean lips ",option:{a:"Hosea ",b:"Jeremiah ",c:"Isaiah ",d:"Micah "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:85,question:"Hosanna means  ",option:{a:"Ride on in majesty ",b:"Ride on Glory ",c:"Ride on to die ",d:"Save me"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:86,question:"The conversion of Paul was made possible by",option:{a:"Simeon ",b:"Zacchaccus ",c:"the risen Lord ",d:"Mathew "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:87,question:"Let his habitation be made desolate, and let there be no one to live in it’ who is being referred to here?  ",option:{a:"King soul ",b:"Judas Iscariot ",c:"Stephen ",d:"Barnabas "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:88,question:"The proconsul when Paul arrived in commit was called",option:{a:"Festus ",b:"portions ",c:"Pilate ",d:"Gallio "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:89,question:"‘Now I known that Lord has sent his angel to deliver me ……”who said this? ",option:{a:"Joseph ",b:"Moses ",c:"Paul ",d:"Peter "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:90,question:"The seven deacons were appointed by ",option:{a:"conduct a mission to the Gentiles",b:"Replace the twelve ",c:"Lead the church in Jerusalem ",d:"Help in the distribution of food "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:91,question:"What did God create on the 6th day ",option:{a:"The firmament ",b:"light ",c:"Dry land and sea ",d:"man and living creatures "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:92,question:"Joshua’s first victory was in ",option:{a:"Ai ",b:"Gibeon ",c:"Jordan ",d:"Giligal "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:93,question:"In the parable of the sower, the seeds on the good ground represent those who ",option:{a:"Accept and live by the world of God ",b:"feed the poor ",c:"Have and love riches ",d:"Give alms in market places "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:94,question:"Which prophet encouraged Jeroboam I to  revolt at the initial stage? ",option:{a:"Micaiah ",b:"Jeremiah ",c:"Nathan ",d:"Joel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:95,question:"‘This had is gone: and where shall I go’ who is being referred to here ",option:{a:"Isaac ",b:"Joseph ",c:"Peter ",d:"Silas "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:96,question:"According to Psalm 51, the sacrifice acceptable to God is",option:{a:"A clean hear ",b:"Obedience ",c:"A blemish less lamb ",d:"A broken spirit "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:97,question:"A would –be apostle who puts his hand to the plaughjsa and looks back lacks ",option:{a:"faith ",b:"Kindness ",c:"Repentance ",d:"Total commitment "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:247,question:"In Timothy, Paul urges Christians to pray for kings and those in authority for the achievement of",option:{a:"a successful Christian life",b:"godly and acceptable life",c:"peace and exaltation in life",d:"quiet and peaceable life."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:248,question:"According to Galatians, one of the benefits of being a joint heir with Christ is having His Spirit in",option:{a:"worship",b:"the heart",c:"the body",d:"prayers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:249,question:"According to Ephesians, children who obey their parents in the Lord will",option:{a:"be happy",b:"go to heaven",c:"have long life",d:"be great."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:250,question:"According to Thessalonians, the day of the Lord will not come unless the",option:{a:"living die first",b:"scoffers come first",c:"dead rise first",d:"rebellion comes first."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:251,question:"In Romans, Paul condemned sin taking over mortal bodies in the new life as instruments of",option:{a:"greediness",b:"wickedness",c:"sadness",d:"foolishness."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:252,question:"In his teaching on partiality, James declares that mercy triumphs over",option:{a:"judgment",b:"righteousness",c:"grace",d:"faith."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:253,question:"In Paul’s arrangement of the spiritual gifts in Corinthians, the last is",option:{a:"the utterance of wisdom",b:"interpretation of tongues",c:"gifts of healing",d:"various kinds of tongues."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:254,question:"In His sermon on the Mount, Jesus said that the poor in spirit are blessed for they would",option:{a:"be satisfied",b:"be comforted on the last day",c:"inherit the kingdom of heaven",d:"inherit the earth."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:255,question:"According to Matthew, the stone on the tomb of Jesus was removed by",option:{a:"an angel",b:"a Roman soldier",c:"Mary Magdalene",d:"Peter and John."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:256,question:"Angel Gabriel told Zachariah that he would become dumb until John was born because he",option:{a:"looked down on the Angel",b:"was advanced in age",c:"disagreed with Elizabeth, his wife",d:"did not believe God’s words."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:257,question:"“...but should write to them to abstain from the pollutions of idols and from unchastity and from what is strangled and from blood...” The statement above was made at the Council of Jerusalem by",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Simon",c:"James",d:"Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:258,question:"In the country of the Gerasenes, Jesus healed the",option:{a:"man possessed of demons",b:"paralytic at the pool",c:"leper",d:"blind man."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:259,question:"Following the death of Stephen, the only group of believers not scattered by the great persecution was the",option:{a:"deacons",b:"apostles",c:"prophets",d:"disciples."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:260,question:"According to Luke, when Moses and Elijah appeared during the Transfiguration, they spoke of Jesus’",option:{a:"departure",b:"second coming",c:"resurrection",d:"trials."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:261,question:"The baptism of Jesus by John in River Jordan was to",option:{a:"convince others that John was His forerunner",b:"ensure that proper baptism must be in a river",c:"service as an example",d:"fulfil all righteousness."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:262,question:"Herod was delighted to see Jesus because he had heard of Him for so long and wanted to",option:{a:"send Him to Rome",b:"sentence Him to death",c:"see Him perform miracles",d:"make Him his friend."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:263,question:"“Do you understand what you are reading?” Philip asked the Ethiopian eunuch the question above when he found him reading the book of",option:{a:"Hosea",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Jeremiah",d:"Isaiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:264,question:"“Unbind him, and let him go.” The statement was made by Jesus when",option:{a:"He raised to life the dead Lazarus",b:"He healed the son of the widow at Nain",c:"He healed the centurion’s servant",d:"a boy bound by Satan was brought to Him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:265,question:"In Luke, at the Last Supper, Jesus revealed His",option:{a:"resurrection",b:"imminent sufferings",c:"love for His disciples",d:"ascension."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:266,question:"The good shepherd according to Jesus is one who",option:{a:"lays down his life for his sheep",b:"goes about with his sheep",c:"keeps many healthy sheep",d:"feeds his sheep in green pastures."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:267,question:"Jesus: stilling of the storm was to",option:{a:"escape from danger",b:"impress His disciples",c:"demonstrate His power",d:"help the fishermen."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:268,question:"“Can any one forbid water for baptizing these people who have received the Holy Spirit just as we have?” The statement above was made by Peter at the conversion of",option:{a:"Herod",b:"Lydia",c:"Saul",d:"Cornelius."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:269,question:"The disciple who replaced Judas Iscariot was",option:{a:"Justus",b:"Stephen",c:"Mathias",d:"Luke."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:270,question:"The message in the parable of the weeds is to",option:{a:"make Christians to be aware of the evil one",b:"remind Christians to pray always",c:"teach Christians to be aware of false teaching",d:"warn Christians on what will happen at the close of age"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:271,question:"The sin of the sons of Eli was that they treated the offering of the LORD with",option:{a:"suspicion",b:"contempt",c:"disgust",d:"jealousy."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:272,question:"In order for the people of Israel to be ready to meet the LORD by the third day at Mount Sinai, they were",option:{a:"not to drink alcohol",b:"to wear white garments",c:"to wash their garments everyday",d:"not to go near a woman."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:273,question:"For worshipping the molten calf, God described the Israelites as",option:{a:"a stubborn nation",b:"an unholy nation",c:"a stiff-necked people",d:"an unrighteous people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:274,question:"“1 will not eat until I have told my errand” In the statement above, the errand of Abraham’s servant was to",option:{a:"find a wife for Isaac",b:"deliver the camels to Laban",c:"assess Isaac’s future wife",d:"deliver Isaac’s message to Laban"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:275,question:"Saul leant from Samuel’s spirit that the LORD would",option:{a:"give the Philistines into his hands",b:"afflict him with sickness",c:"because Isaac’s future wife",d:"pardon his iniquity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:276,question:"“My spirit shall not abide in man forever, for he is flesh...” When God made the statement above, He concluded that man’s days shall be",option:{a:"one hundred years",b:"one hundred and fifty years",c:"eighty years",d:"one hundred and twenty years."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:277,question:"According to proverbs, a son that is attentive to a father’s instruction will",option:{a:"be rich",b:"have eternal life",c:"gain insight",d:"be forgiven his sins"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:278,question:"When God called Moses to deliver the Israelites, he resisted because he could not speak and he was told to",option:{a:"perform some signs with his rod",b:"wait for a sign from God",c:"go with Joshua who would speak for him",d:"go with Aaron who would speak for him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:279,question:"David was anointed king over Judah at",option:{a:"Zuph",b:"Bethlehem",c:"Hebron",d:"Gibeon."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:280,question:"“Behold, if people of Israel are to come, let us deal shrewdly with them, lest they multiply.....” ln the statement, the first step by the king of Egypt was to",option:{a:"cast all Hebrew male children into the Nile",b:"impose heavy tax on them",c:"kill Hebrew male children",d:"set taskmasters over them to afflict them with burdens"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:281,question:"“Let the waters under the heavens be gathered together into one place, and let the dry land appear.” In the statement above  the dry land and the water refer to",option:{a:"earth and oceans",b:"firmament and seas",c:"firmament and oceans",d:"earth and seas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:282,question:"What did Gideon call the altar which he built to the LORD?",option:{a:"The LORD is merciful",b:"The LORD is peace",c:"Jehovah Jireh",d:"The LORD is great"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:283,question:"When King Nebuchadnezzar besieged Judah, he took away all classes of people but spared the",option:{a:"poorest people of the land",b:"palace guards",c:"children and the aged",d:"priests and prophets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:284,question:"After Prophet Ezekiel had eaten what he was offered, he was sent to speak to",option:{a:"a people of hard language",b:"the house of Israel",c:"the house of Judah",d:"a people of foreign language"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:285,question:"Josiah believed that the wrath of the LORD was kindled against him and all Judah because",option:{a:"they did not observe the Passover",b:"there was an unholy thing in their midst",c:"the people have forgotten God",d:"their fathers were disobedient to God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:286,question:"“Son of man, stand upon your feet, and I will speak with you.” What happened to the Son of man after the instruction above?",option:{a:"The Spirit entered him.",b:"He became terrified.",c:"The angels gave him support.",d:"He began to prophesy."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:287,question:"God had pity on the people of Nineveh because",option:{a:"they listened to Jonah’s message",b:"the king punished all the violent people in the land",c:"they turned from their evil way.",d:"they made sacrifices of sin offering to God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:288,question:"The Kingdom of Israel was divided because the",option:{a:"kingdom was too large to be administered",b:"leadership wanted to create more nations",c:"followership wanted more nations",d:"last two kings made unwise policies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:289,question:"“Behold, I am the LORD, the God of all flesh; is anything too hard for me...” The statement above suggests that God is",option:{a:"merciful",b:"awesome",c:"most powerful",d:"not changeable."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:290,question:"Immediately after the contest on Mount Carmel, Elijah prayed and God answered him with",option:{a:"thunder",b:"rainfall",c:"a whirlwind",d:"a heavy storm."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:291,question:"Prophet Amos told Israel to hate evil, love good and establish justice in the gate so that God would",option:{a:"heal their diseases",b:"give them good leaders",c:"be gracious to them",d:"multiply their descendants."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:292,question:"In addition to the declaration of freedom to the exiles in Babylon, King Cyrus ordered for",option:{a:"free will offering for the house of God in Jerusalem",b:"the release of Jewish, slaves in the empire",c:"security check on the Jews before departure",d:"support from craftsmen in Babylon."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:293,question:"“Am I God, to kill and to make alive, that this man sends words to me to cure a man of his leprosy...” Prophet Elisha responded to the king’s reaction in the statement above by",option:{a:"directing the nation of Israel to pray and fast",b:"requesting the leper to come to his house",c:"directing the leper to go to River Jordan",d:"asking the leper to offer a sacrifice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:294,question:"According to Prophet Jeremiah, one of the promises of God was that He would give the Israelites",option:{a:"new priests",b:"new commandments",c:"kings after His own heart",d:"shepherds after His own heart."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:295,question:"Prophet Hosea named his second child Not Pitied because God would no more pity the",option:{a:"kings of Judah",b:"kings of Israel",c:"house of Judah",d:"house of Israel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:296,question:"“Test your servants for ten days; let us be given vegetables to eat and water to drink...” In the statement above, Daniel was talking to",option:{a:"King Darius",b:"the chief of the eunuchs",c:"the steward of the chief eunuch.",d:"King Artaxerxes."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:446,question:"What in the creation account, gave man an edge over every other creature?",option:{a:"Other creatures were made for man",b:"Man alone was created in the Image of God",c:"Man had the rare privilege to dwell in Eden",d:"Satan acknowledged his privileged position"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:447,question:"At Shechem, God appeared to Abram and told him that",option:{a:"he should continue on his journey southward.",b:"he should leave his country and Kindred.",c:"the land would be given to his descendants.",d:"in the land he should build an altar."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:448,question:"In their dealings with God, Abraham and Sarah learnt the 	following lessons except that God is",option:{a:"able to bless the righteous.",b:"faithful to His promise",c:"all powerful-nothing is too hard for Him.",d:"not in a hurry to carry out His promises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:449,question:"Pharaoh’s horsemen and his army overtook the fleeing Hebrews encamped by the sea at",option:{a:"Migdol.",b:"Etham.",c:"Phiahiroth.",d:"Meriba."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:450,question:"The episode of David and Bathsheba, Uriah’s wife was in 	violation of God’s",option:{a:"sixth commandment.",b:"seventh commandment,",c:"eight commandment.",d:"ninth commandment."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:451,question:"When the people of Israel received the encouraging report 	given by two of the twelve spies, they decided to",option:{a:"stone Moses for taking them out of Egypt.",b:"choose Caleb as their leader and go back to Egypt.",c:"stone the two spies who gave the report.",d:"raise an army to fight the Canaanites."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:452,question:"Which of the following tribes accompanied Deborah and Barak to the war against Jabin and Sisera?",option:{a:"Naphtali and Zebulum",b:"Issachar and Reuben",c:"Ephraim and Dan",d:"Judah and Benjamin"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:453,question:"On matters of parental responsibility, Samuel could not be commended because he",option:{a:"made his children judges instead of priests.",b:"wanted his children to succeed him.",c:"did nothing to stop his children’s immoral behaviours.",d:"did not care what happened to Israel after his death."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:454,question:"Eli, the priest in Shiloh, was condemned because he",option:{a:"allowed his children to deprive God of His share of sacrifice.",b:"allowed the Ark of God to be taken to the battle field",c:"did not take God’s message through Samuel seriously.",d:"officiated at the temple without the assistance of the prophet."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:455,question:"David’s first Contact with Saul was because he was",option:{a:"skillful in playing.",b:"victorious over Goliath.",c:"a man of valour.",d:"a shepherd boy."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:456,question:"David showed Nathan the prophet that he had repented of his sin by",option:{a:"refusing to marry Uriah’s wife.",b:"confessing that he had sinned.",c:"offering to compensate Uriah’s family",d:"making sacrifice to please God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:457,question:"Elijah was a prophet during the reign of",option:{a:"Gideon.",b:"David.",c:"Ahab.",d:"Rehoboam."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:458,question:"When God ordered famine on Israel, Elijah was fed by the ravens at",option:{a:"Brook Cherith.",b:"River Jordan.",c:"River Kishon",d:"Mount Carmel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:459,question:"“The Lord forbid that I should give you the inheritance of my fathers”. The inheritance referred to here is",option:{a:"birth right.",b:"the world.",c:"the kingship.",d:"a vineyard."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:460,question:"The king of Judah who suffered in the hands of Nebuchadnezzar was",option:{a:"Jehoachin.",b:"Manasseh.",c:"Josiah.",d:"Zedekiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:461,question:"The punishment of Israel according to the vision of Jeremiah includes all the following except",option:{a:"occupation of the land by foreigners.",b:"restoration of their kings and priests.",c:"destruction of their flocks and herds.",d:"consumption of their harvest by their enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:462,question:"Complete this statement “Holy, Holy, Holy is the Lord of Hosts,",option:{a:"the Seraphim’s bow to His glory”.",b:"the whole earth will sing His glory”.",c:"the whole earth is full of His glory”.",d:"His creatures will rise to praise His Holy name”."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:463,question:"When Isaiah saw the Lord in His holiness and glory, he exclaimed",option:{a:"“Blessed is me for 1 am truly holy”.",b:"“Woe is me! For I am lost”",c:"“Blessed be the name of the Lord”.",d:"“I am finished, for I have seen a holy God”."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:464,question:"Jeremiah said the people of Judah were in a state of mourning because,",option:{a:"they sinned against God.",b:"their vessels were empty",c:"their farms were destroyed.",d:"there was drought in the land."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:465,question:"The king planned to set Daniel over the whole kingdom because,",option:{a:"he was the most educated of all.",b:"an excellent spirit was in him.",c:"he wanted to favour a foreigner.",d:"Daniel brought information to the king."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:466,question:"God spoke through Amos that He would punish Israel for the following sins except that they",option:{a:"sold the righteous for silver.",b:"sold the needy for a pair of shoes.",c:"trampled the head of the poor into the dust.",d:"pursued their brothers with the swords."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:467,question:"The first batch of Jewish exiles to rebuild the temple was under the leadership of",option:{a:"Joshua.",b:"Hanani.",c:"Sheshbazzar.",d:"Zerubabel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:468,question:"Which two tribes in Israel led in the rebuilding of the temple after the exile?",option:{a:"Judah and Benjamin",b:"Naphtali and Joseph",c:"Manasseh and Reuben",d:"Judah and Ephraim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:469,question:"After his baptism Jesus began to",option:{a:"proclaim the kingdom of God.",b:"baptize others.",c:"confront religious leaders.",d:"teach in parables."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:470,question:"The devout man in Jerusalem whom the Lord promised would see Christ before his death was named",option:{a:"Zechariah.",b:"Joseph.",c:"Stephen",d:"Simeon."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:471,question:"Jesus ordered the seventy disciples not to salute any one because",option:{a:"their mission required urgency.",b:"it is not part of their mission to salute people.",c:"they may forget their mission.",d:"salutations to strangers defile the Jews."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:472,question:"Jesus teaches, “Let your light so shine before men...” By light Jesus refers to,",option:{a:"the Christian character and virtues in us.",b:"the bright lights at the altar in the church.",c:"the light that shows the right way.",d:"our knowledge of the scripture."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:473,question:"“And if anyone will not receive you or listen to your words, shake off the dust from your feet as you leave that house.” This is a sign of",option:{a:"forgiveness",b:"rebuke",c:"acceptance",d:"condemnation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:474,question:"“Foxes have holes and birds of the air have nets; but the son of man has nowhere to lay His head”. By this statement, Jesus meant that His disciples",option:{a:"would not grow rich.",b:"would not enjoy good houses.",c:"had a lot of task ahead.",d:"had a lot of enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:475,question:"The treasures which Jesus wants us to lay in heaven include",option:{a:"generosity and kindness.",b:"love and mercy.",c:"works of righteousness",d:"gold and silver."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:476,question:"“No one can serve two masters...” This means that one should not",option:{a:"be idolatrous.",b:"belong to two religions.",c:"worship money.",d:"bean unbeliever."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:477,question:"Whoever drinks the water Jesus gives will never thirst? What is this water?",option:{a:"The spirit of God.",b:"Holy and anointed water.",c:"The word of God.",d:"Law of God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:478,question:"Jesus said “I am the bread of life; he who comes to me shall not hunger...” ‘Bread of life’ in this context means the",option:{a:"body of Jesus Christ.",b:"manna given to the Israelites.",c:"holy bread of life.",d:"spiritual food through Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:479,question:"John’s summary of God’s love for the world is that He",option:{a:"sent his son to judge the world righteously.",b:"created man in his own image with authority.",c:"made light that the world might walk in it.",d:"gave his only son to save all believers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:480,question:"According to John’s Gospel, Lazarus was from",option:{a:"Bethany",b:"Galilee.",c:"Jerusalem.",d:"Bethsaida."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:481,question:"Jesus said to Martha, “...and whoever live and believes in me shall never die...” Jesus talks about",option:{a:"physical death.",b:"spiritual death.",c:"emotional death.",d:"natural death."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:482,question:"The meeting of the Christian Council of Jerusalem was chaired by",option:{a:"Peter.",b:"Paul.",c:"James.",d:"John."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:483,question:"Paul wished to retain Onesimus with him but did not do so because",option:{a:"Onesimus was unwilling to stay with him.",b:"he was afraid of Philemon’s reaction.",c:"he did not like such a favour to be imposed on Philemon.",d:"Onesimus would soon be released from jail."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:484,question:"Paul and his associates gave the Thessalonian believers an 	important example to imitate. This example was to",option:{a:"be ready to help the poor always",b:"toil, labour and work to earn a living",c:"depend on foreign aids for sustenance.",d:"suffer imprisonment without complaint."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:485,question:"Peter urged all Christians to endure sufferings in faith conscious of the fact that",option:{a:"Jesus, himself also resisted suffering",b:"the devil could lure them from faith with suffering.",c:"only the physical body is affected.",d:"suffering is temporary and leads to eternal glory."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:486,question:"Paul’s teaching in Colossians on love, respect and obedience concerns",option:{a:"Christian giving.",b:"family relationship.",c:"master servant relationship.",d:"Christian relations with their enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:487,question:"According to Peter, God set up the state for the purpose of",option:{a:"silencing the ignorance of foolish men.",b:"collecting appropriate taxes from its citizens",c:"carrying out appropriate sanctions for the guilty",d:"ensuring the protection of its citizens"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:488,question:"In Paul’s epistle to the Thessalonians, any Christian living 	in idleness should be",option:{a:"thrown out of the Church.",b:"looked at as an enemy.",c:"sympathized with",d:"avoided by the others."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:489,question:"The two major obstacles against Abraham’s hope for a son were",option:{a:"impotency and old age",b:"faithlessness and unbelief.",c:"old age and barrenness.",d:"sin and doubt."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:490,question:"The theme justification by faith can only be achieved through",option:{a:"sacrifices to Jesus.",b:"resurrection of Jesus.",c:"redemptive power of Jesus.",d:"response of angels to Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:491,question:"According to Paul in Romans, if it is the adherents of the law who are to be the heirs of Abraham then faith in Jesus is",option:{a:"null and void.",b:"not attainable",c:`.     			
beyond the reach of Gentiles`,d:"transgression of the law."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,i as default,t as status,e as subject,o as total};
